A Guide to the Speech File of the University News Service and the Office Of Information Services, 1929-1961
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Speech File of the University News Service and the Office Of Information Services 1929-1961
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-4/2/5.491
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Stored off-site. Users must request boxes 48 hours in advance of desired use. Neither drop-in nor next-day requests can be fulfilled. For additional information, contact Special Collections.
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library between 1948-1968.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of the Speech File of the University News Service and the Office Of Information Services.
Contents List
- Abbott, Charles C., Education for Business, Charlottesville Chamber of Commerce 1954 Nov 4 (Box 1)
- Andrews, T. Coleman, Teaching Taxes, Institute for Math Teachers 1953 Aug 5 (Box 1)
- Archer, Cooper, Hebel, Kroll, Cunningham, Lead Glass Fabric, abstract n.d. (Box 1)
- Bebout, John E., Thomas Jefferson, His Message to America, radio program script, WAAT, Newark, New Jersey 1943 April 8 (Box 1)
- Berkner, Lloyd V., The Impact of Science on Strategy, Institute of Public Affairs 1951 July 11 (Box 1)
- Biddle, Francis, Notes on Democratic Thinking, William H. White Foundation Lecture 1942 Dec. 4 (Box 1)
- Blackford, Dr. Staige D., untitled commencement address, Medical School 1945 Jun (Box 1)
- Bowers, Claude G., untitled, unveiling of James Monroe statue, Charlottesville, Virginia 1932 Apr 25 (Box 1)
- Butler, Paul M., untitled, Virginia Legal Forum 1956 Oct 9 (Box 1)
- Buttrick, G. A., New Commandment, Baccalaureate address 1951 Jun 10 (Box 1)
- Carmichael, O. C., The University and the National Defense, Convocation 1940 Oct 2 (Box 1)
- Clapp, Gordon R., Aid to Underdeveloped Areas, Institute of Public Affairs 1951 Jul 10 (Box 1)
- Davis, Watson, Science's Next Great Steps, Alpha Chi Sigma of the University of Virginia 1949 May 5 (Box 1)
- Dos Passos, John, Suppose Jefferson Were Alive Today, Jefferson Society 1957 April 12 (Box 1)
- Dunham, Franklin, The Radio and Public Response, National Conference of Jews and Christians, Mass. 1937 Sep 3 (Box 1)
- Elliott, William Y., Summary of Remarks, Institute of Public Affairs 1951 July 12 (Box 1)
- Fernandez, Romeo, The Philippine Election1953 Nov 1 (Box 1)
- Gee, Wilson, Culture in Democracy, North Carolina Library Association meeting 1929 Apr 4 (Box 1)
- Guerry, Dupont III, [Unnatural Bleeding and Vitamin K], John Horsley Memorial Prize 1940 Apr (Box 1)
- Hanania, Fanid, The Tensions Between the Arab Near East and Western Democracies1953 Feb 10 (Box 1)
- Hanke, Lewis, Bartolomé de Los Casas: 'Protector of the Indians' (I, III), James W. Richards Lectures in History 1948 (Box 1)
- Haskins, Caryl, Mr. Jefferson's Sacred Gardens, Founders Day 1967 Apr 13 (Box 1)
- Jouett, E. S., Remarks, D.A.R., Jack Jouett Chapter meeting 1936 Jul 4 (Box 1)
- Kamel, Mostafa-untitled, Student Legal Forum 1959 Nov 6 (Box 1)
- Kilmuir, Viscount, Individual Freedom Under an Unwritten Constitution, Doherty Foundation Lecture 1959 Apr 17 (Box 1)
- Lewis, Ivey F., Biological Principles and National Policy, American Association for the Advancement of Science, Philadelphia 1951 Dec (Box 1)
- Lilienthal, David E., The Citizen as Public Servant, Commencement address 1948 Jun 14 (Box 1)
- Lover, Myron J., Thermodynamic Aspects of Gravithermals1951 (Box 1)
- Nelson, Robert O., The Public School and the University, Commencement address 1952 Aug 16 (Box 1)
- Perry, Marvin, So You Want to Go to College, radio script, WLVA-TV 1961 Mar 21 (Box 1)
- Poole, Sidney, Planetary Thrombosisn.d. (Box 1)
- Powers, Joshua B., t: [ Developments in Argentina Since 1955,] for Woodrow Wilson Department of Foreign Affairs 1957 Mar 15 (Box 1)
- Riegel, O. W., Propaganda and the Role of the College Publicity Director, Conference of American College Publicity Association [at the University of Virginia] 1941 Mar 7 (Box 1)
- [Robertson, A. Willis], untitled commencement address [1954 Jun 14] (Box 1)
- Robertson, Walter S., Report to the Founder on Foreign Affairs, Founder's Day 1957 Apr 13 (Box 1)
- Rountrey, J. Edward, Downtown Assessments, Local Government Officials Conference 1954 Aug 24 (Box 1)
- Schuman, Robert, European Integration and the Atlantic Alliance1958 Mar 31 (Box 1)
- Stassen, Harold E., MIM Speech, Why Virginia Democrats Should Vote for President Eisenhower on Election Day, public forum at the University of Virginia 1956 Oct 9 (Box 1)
- Staffacher, Beams, Snoddy, A New Analytical Centrifugen.d. (Box 1)
- Stettinius, Edward R., untitled, Convocation 1946 Oct 12 (Box 1)
- Stevenson, Adlai, untitled, Founder's Day 1960 Apr 12 (Box 1)
- Stiles, Lindley J., Controversial Issues in American Life, American Association of School Administrators/National Council for the social Studies/NEA Department of Classroom Teachers n.d. (Box 1)
- Stiles, Lindley J., Graduation Extension Teachingn.d. (Box 1)
- Stiles, Lindley J., Our Children Cannot Wait, Virginia Congress of Parents and Teachers, Bristol, Virginia 1953 Oct 20 (Box 1)
- Thompson, Lorin A., Some Economic Aspects of Virginia's Current Educational Crisis1958 (Box 1)
- Toynbee, Arnold, The Colonial Question, public address 1958 Apr 16 (Box 1)
- Wallace, Henry A., Thomas Jefferson: Farmer, Educator, and Democrat, Monticello speech, 75th Anniversaries of Land Grant College and USDA [1938 Nov 16] (Box 1)
- Whitehead, Robert, Leadership in Public Affairs, Omicron Delta Kappa Society, Omicron Delta Kappa Society banquet 1951 May 10 (Box 2)
- Windolph, F. Lyman, Religio Advocati, Phi Betta Kappa address n.d. (Box 2)
- Wranek, William H., The City of Lynchburg Celebrates its Sesquicentennial[1936] (Box 2)
- Wranek, William H., Crust news reports 1946-1947 (Box 2)
- Wranek, William H., Jefferson and Monticellon.d. (Box 2)
- Wranek, William H., Public Relations in Action Colleges and Universities, All-Virginia Public Relations Conference, Richmond 1949 May 12 (Box 2)
- Wranke, William H., untitled, radio talks 1937-1938 (Box 2)
- Wright, David M., Freedom and the Administrative Senaten.d. (Box 2)
- Wynne, J. P., Aims of General Education1951 (Box 2)
- Zirkle, Conway, Our Splintered Learning and the Status of Scientists, Phi Beta Kappa address to AAAS, Berkeley, California 1954 Dec 27 (Box 2)
- The Camel Caravan with Vaughn Monroe, CBS radio script 1949 Apr 23 (Box 2)
- Cavalier radio news scripts 1947 Feb-Mar (Box 2)
- The General Electric Packaged Heat Pump n.d. (Box 2)
- George Washington, Builder of the Republic, American Good Government Society n.d. (Box 2)
- German Trainees-Comments, newspaper excerpts 1950 Jun 29 (Box 2)
- Jefferson and the Romantic Culture n.d. (Box 2)
- Local Government Officials' Conference, welcome speech 1954 Aug (Box 2)
- The Problems of Good and Evil, introduction, Series of Theology Lectures, No. 11. 1954 (Box 2)
- Some Social Problems Arising from Industrialization n.d. (Box 2)
- Trends in Education n.d. (Box 2)
- World Tension and the Far East n.d. (Box 2)